<oml:data_set_description xmlns:oml="http://openml.org/openml">
  <oml:id>1535</oml:id>
  <oml:name>volcanoes-b5</oml:name>
  <oml:version>1</oml:version>
  <oml:description>**Author**: Michael C. Burl 
**Source**: UCI  
**Please cite**:   

* Dataset Title:  
Volcanoes on Venus - JARtool experiment Data Set  
Experiment: B5        

* Source:

Michael C. Burl 
MS 126-347, JPL 
4800 Oak Grove Drive 
Pasadena, CA 91109 
(818) 393-5345 
Michael.C.Burl '@' jpl.nasa.gov 
http://www-aig.jpl.nasa.gov/mls/home/burl/


* Data Set Information:  

The data was collected by the Magellan spacecraft over an approximately four year period from 1990--1994. The objective of the mission was to obtain global mapping of the surface of Venus using synthetic aperture radar (SAR). A more detailed discussion of the mission and objectives is available at JPL's Magellan webpage. 

There are some spatial dependencies. For example, background patches from with in a single image are likely to be more similar than background patches taken across different images. 

In addition to the images, there are &quot;ground truth&quot; files that specify the locations of volcanoes within the images. The quotes around &quot;ground truth&quot; are intended as a reminder that there is no absolute ground truth for this data set. No one has been to Venus and the image quality does not permit 100%, unambiguous identification of the volcanoes, even by human experts. There are labels that provide some measure of subjective uncertainty (1 = definitely a volcano, 2 = probably, 3 = possibly, 4 = only a pit is visible). See reference [Smyth95] for more information on the labeling uncertainty problem. 

There are also files that specify the exact set of experiments using in the published evaluations of the JARtool system. 

* Attribute Information:

The images are 1024X1024 pixels. The pixel values are in the range [0,255]. The pixel value is related to the amount of energy backscattered to the radar from a given spatial location. Higher pixel values indicate greater backscatter. Lower pixel values indicate lesser backscatter. Both topography and surface roughness relative to the radar wavelength affect the amount of backscatter.


* Relevant Papers:

G.H. Pettengill, P.G. Ford, W.T.K. Johnson, R.K. Raney, L.A. Soderblom, &quot;Magellan: Radar Performance and Data Products&quot;, Science, 252:260-265 (1991). 

R.S. Saunders, A.J. Spear, P.C. Allin, R.S. Austin, A.L. Berman, R.C. Chandlee, J. Clark, A.V. Decharon, E.M. Dejong, &quot;Magellan Mission Summary&quot;, J. of Geophysical Research Planets, 97(E8):13067-13090, (1992). 

M.C. Burl, L. Asker, P. Smyth, U. Fayyad, P. Perona, L. Crumpler, and J. Aubele, &quot;Learning to Recognize Volcanoes on Venus&quot;, Machine Learning, (March 1998). 

P. Smyth, M.C. Burl, U.M. Fayyad, and P. Perona, Chapter: &quot;Knowledge Discovery in Large Image Databases: Dealing with Uncertainties in Ground Truth&quot;, In Advances in Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining, AAAI/MIT Press, Menlo Park, CA, (1995). </oml:description>
  <oml:description_version>1</oml:description_version>
  <oml:format>ARFF</oml:format>
        <oml:upload_date>2015-06-01T19:32:34</oml:upload_date>
    <oml:licence>Public</oml:licence>  <oml:url>https://api.openml.org/data/v1/download/1593731/volcanoes-b5.arff</oml:url>
  <oml:parquet_url>http://openml1.win.tue.nl/dataset1535/dataset_1535.pq</oml:parquet_url>  <oml:file_id>1593731</oml:file_id>  <oml:default_target_attribute>Class</oml:default_target_attribute>          <oml:tag>study_52</oml:tag><oml:tag>study_7</oml:tag>  <oml:visibility>public</oml:visibility>      <oml:minio_url>http://openml1.win.tue.nl/dataset1535/dataset_1535.pq</oml:minio_url>  <oml:status>active</oml:status>
  <oml:processing_date>2020-11-20 21:57:21</oml:processing_date>      <oml:md5_checksum>d1600f81b07892abf061b3de16efb882</oml:md5_checksum>
</oml:data_set_description>
