<oml:data_set_description xmlns:oml="http://openml.org/openml">
  <oml:id>40705</oml:id>
  <oml:name>tokyo1</oml:name>
  <oml:version>1</oml:version>
  <oml:description>**Author**: Ron Kohavi   
**Source**: [SGI.com tech archive](http://www.sgi.com/tech/mlc/db/) (no longer available, [copy on GitHub](https://github.com/acefoxy/DataScience/blob/973d9239ca3190487204ce8037a1d3c8689f95dd/week2/www.sgi.com/tech/mlc/db/tokyo1.names
)), [PMLB](https://github.com/EpistasisLab/penn-ml-benchmarks/tree/master/datasets/classification/tokyo1)  
**Please cite**:  

**Tokyo SGI Server Performance Data**  
This is Performance co-pilot (PCP) data for the Tokyo server at Silicon Graphics International (SGI). 
It characterizes the server performance as either `good` (1) or `bad` (0).

The instances are measurements generated by the PCP software every five seconds. See the [PCP manual](http://www.irix7.com/techpubs/007-2614-001.pdf) for further details.

### Attribute Information  
The attributes are interpreted as follows:  
- runq: Average number of runnable processes in main memory (mem) and in swap memory (swp) during the interval.
- memory: The free column indicates average free memory during the interval, in Kilobytes. The page column is the average number of page out operations per second during the interval. I/O operations caused by these page-out operations are included in the write I/O rate.
- system: System call rate (scall), context switch rate (ctxsw) and interrupt rate (intr). Rates are expressed as average operations per second during the interval.
- disks: Aggregated physical read (rd) and write (wr) rates over all disks, expressed as physical I/O operations issued per second during the interval. These rates are independent of the I/O block size.
- cpu: Percentage of CPU time spent executing user code (usr), system and interrupt code (sys), idle loop (idl) and idle waiting for resources, typically disk I/O (wt).
</oml:description>
  <oml:description_version>1</oml:description_version>
  <oml:format>ARFF</oml:format>
        <oml:upload_date>2017-04-06T12:38:44</oml:upload_date>
    <oml:licence>public</oml:licence>  <oml:url>https://api.openml.org/data/v1/download/4965306/tokyo1.arff</oml:url>
  <oml:parquet_url>http://openml1.win.tue.nl/dataset40705/dataset_40705.pq</oml:parquet_url>  <oml:file_id>4965306</oml:file_id>  <oml:default_target_attribute>class</oml:default_target_attribute>          <oml:tag>study_144</oml:tag>  <oml:visibility>public</oml:visibility>      <oml:minio_url>http://openml1.win.tue.nl/dataset40705/dataset_40705.pq</oml:minio_url>  <oml:status>active</oml:status>
  <oml:processing_date>2018-10-04 07:16:35</oml:processing_date>      <oml:md5_checksum>3402d02e52d3a1bbf44c6e5df98942b4</oml:md5_checksum>
</oml:data_set_description>
